Aadil Girach

155 Hillcrest Ave, Apt #1003 • Mississauga, L5B 3Z2 • 647-609-7396 • aagirach8@gmail.com

Profile

Detail oriented Mechanical Engineering student with excellent research and design skills, programming knowledge and over 4 years of experience in modelling/designing 2D and 3D models.

Technical Skills

Programming and simulations: Arduino Uno, Matlab, Simulink, Arena

Engineering Design and analysis: AutoCAD, Solidworks, FMEA, DFA, DFMA

Other: MS Office (Word, PowerPoint, Excel, Project, Visio) Equipment: CNC machining, Optical Measurement, CMM

Education

Ryerson University, Toronto ON

(Graduating in Oct 2018)

Bachelor of Engineering, Mechanical

Minor: Marketing

Mechanical Engineering Design Projects

Capstone (Autonomous Solar Panel Cleaning Robot)

January 2018 – April 2018

- Working in a group of 3 going through the design process to create a new product that would clean the dust and debris off the solar panel
- Product was designed for arid locations, will be autonomous, easy to use, low maintenance and a ten years life span
- Several designs were created to meet the requirements, each of them analyzed and discussed with the supervisor to come with the optimal design.
- Weekly meetings are held for show of work and research conducted regarding the project

Design projects for Manufacturing/Ergonomics

January 2016 – April 2018

- Worked on multiple projects with the primary goal to make the product ergonomic and easy to manufacture
- Use DFMA (Design for Manufacturing and Assembly) software to give an accurate information on cost of manufacture
- Conducted several analyses to determine the optimal design for the right price.

Trailer Dolly

January 2016 – April 2016

- Designed a trailer dolly to haul up to 10,000 lbs of trailer load
- Several analyses were carried out to make sure the strength and integrity of the product. Shaft design analysis, design of various mechanical elements and failure prevention
- Stress and strain simulations were done on Solidworks after appropriate material was applied

Professional Experience

Volunteer – Aerospace Course Union

September 2016 – April 2018

Ryerson University

- Work under the president and with other executives to plan events through out the year
- Help them market the event through social media and always aimed and achieved to increase the number of attendees.
- Aid the VP of communications with creating the Union's logo, branded clothing and general upkeep of the office.

Industrial Engineering Director Assistant

September 2015 – April 2016

Ryerson University

- Coordinate with the Director and other colleagues, assist in developing and implementing plans and goals for department.
- Delegate duties such as typing, copying, help spread propaganda for planned events
- Work with the Director at events to manage administrative functions to ensure smooth and efficient operations
- Assist in budgeting and monitoring expenses
- Maintain scheduling of events and represent the RESS (Ryerson Engineering Student Society) when needed

Sales Associate

October 2013 - December 2013

The Hudson Bay, Toronto

- Always greeting customers on the sales floor and help them with utmost degree of satisfaction
- Wearing formal attire and always maintaining a professional environment with the customers.
- Having the knowledge of the details of individual company's luggage.

Sales Associate

March 2013- April 2013

Bed, Bath and Beyond

- Converse with the customer and make sure the customer is satisfied with their sales experience.
- Being knowledgeable about the products of the sales floor, to recommend products depending on the customers budget and usage.
- Receiving shipment and taking them to their designated areas.
- Communicating ideas with the department manager, in attempt to make the department/area look better.